Class of 1882 Records, 1870-1959, 2000
Smith College Archives
Class of 1882 Records
1870-1959, 2000
Smith College. Class of 1882.
RG 80 UUID:c3b70da7-acda-492d-b099-d7577970b0b9
7 boxes (2 linear feet)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains letters, correspondence, black and white photographs, scrapbooks, student notes, and materials from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1882.
Historical Note
The Class of 1882 was the fourth graduating class of Smith College.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Class of 1882 Records contain materials describing the history of the Class of 1882. Types of materials include letters, correspondence, black and white photographs, scrapbooks, student notes, and materials from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1882.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1882 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class of 1882: Class Essay 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 1)
- Class of 1882: Class Letters 1913, 1925 (Box 1392, Folder 2)
- Class of 1882: Class Officers (Correspondence and Finances) 1908-10, 1912, 1922 (Box 1392, Folder 3)
- Class of 1882: Class Supper 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 4)
- Class of 1882: Commencement Poems 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 5)
- Class of 1882: Commencement 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 6)
- Class of 1882: Commencement Music 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 7)
- Class of 1882: Commencement Speaker 1881-82 (Box 1392, Folder 8)
- Class of 1882: Group Photos 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 9)
- Class of 1882: History 1879, 1882, other n.d. (Box 1392, Folder 10)
- Class of 1882: Photographer Records 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 11)
- Class of 1882: Records 1878-1882 (Box 1392, Folder 12)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1889) 1889 (Box 1392, Folder 13)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1907) 1907 (Box 1392, Folder 14)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1910) 1910 (Box 1392, Folder 15)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1912) 1912 (Box 1392, Folder 16)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1917) 1917 (Box 1392, Folder 17)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1922) 1922 (Box 1392, Folder 18)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1927) 1927 (Box 1392, Folder 19)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1932) 1932 (Box 1392, Folder 20)
- Class of 1882: Reunions (1942) 1942 (Box 1392, Folder 21)
- Class of 1882: Senior Reception 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 22)
- Class of 1882: Songs 1882 (Box 1392, Folder 23)
- Class of 1882: Sophomore Reception 1879 (Box 1392, Folder 24)
- Class of 1882: Statistics N.d. (Box 1392, Folder 25)
- Class of 1882: Alden, Mary Elizabeth 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 1)
- Class of 1882: Allen, Annie Elizabeth 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 2)
- Class of 1882: Ayres, Edith Jane 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 3)
- Class of 1882: Blake, Isabel (Correspondence, Jan-Mar) 1878 (Box 1393, Folder 4)
- Class of 1882: Blake, Isabel (Correspondence, Sept-Oct) 1878 (Box 1393, Folder 5)
- Class of 1882: Blake, Isabel (Correspondence, Nov-Dec) 1878 (Box 1393, Folder 6)
- Class of 1882: Blake, Isabel (Correspondence, Jan-Mar) 1879 (Box 1393, Folder 7)
- Class of 1882: Blake, Isabel (Letters) 1879-81, 1909-10 (Box 1393, Folder 8)
- Class of 1882: Blake, Isabel (Photographs) 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 9)
- Class of 1882: Blanchard, Grace 1882, 1921, 1933-34 (Box 1393, Folder 10)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Box 1393, Folder 11)
- Class of 1882: Brown, Fanny Chamberlain 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 12)
- Class of 1882: Browne, Nina Eliza (Box 1393, Folder 13)
- Class of 1882: Cheever, Ellen Tyler 1878-79, 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 14)
- Class of 1882: Clark, Sophia Cook 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 15)
- Class of 1882: Clarke, Mary Reynolds 1882, 1959 (Box 1393, Folder 16)
- Class of 1882: Craig, Jean Maria 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 17)
- Class of 1882: Daniels, Mary Bryant (General) 1904-05 (Box 1393, Folder 18)
- Class of 1882: Daniels, Mary Bryant (Photographs) 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 19)
- Class of 1882: Eastman, Maria Rebecca 1882, other n.d. (Box 1393, Folder 20)
- Class of 1882: Eppendorf, Lina 1945 (Box 1393, Folder 21)
- Class of 1882: Fitch, Laura Forbes 1882, 1914-15, 1918, 1926 (Box 1393, Folder 22)
- Class of 1882: Gardner, Ada Grant 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 23)
- Class of 1882: Girdler, Lydia Louise 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 24)
- Class of 1882: Goodell, May Evelyn 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 25)
- Class of 1882: Goodwin, Clara Kenrick 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 26)
- Class of 1882: Greene, Grace Miller 1882, 1929, 1931, 1940-41, 1948-49 (Box 1393, Folder 27)
- Class of 1882: Gulliver, Mary 1882, 1922, 1934 (Box 1393, Folder 28)
- Class of 1882: Hammond, Mary Grace 1882, 1911, 1914 (Box 1393, Folder 29)
- Class of 1882: Hayes, Clara Louise 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 30)
- Class of 1882: Hidden, Mary Belle 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 31)
- Class of 1882: Huggins, Mary Augusta 1884, 1916, 1923 (Box 1393, Folder 32)
- Class of 1882: Hungerford, Caroline Marsh 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 33)
- Class of 1882: Jackson, Annie Brown (Letters) 1881, 1888-89 (Box 1393, Folder 34)
- Class of 1882: Jackson, Annie Brown (Photographs) 1882, 1889, 1892, 1916, 1919, 1921, 1923-24 (Box 1393, Folder 35)
- Class of 1882: Jackson, Annie Brown ("Mediaeval France and the Troubadours") (Box 1393, Folder 36)
- Class of 1882: Jameson, Mary 1882, 1930 (Box 1393, Folder 37)
- Class of 1882: Kellogg, Sarah Delano (Box 1393, Folder 38)
- Class of 1882: King, Fanny 1882 (Box 1393, Folder 39)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Nellie Rose 2000 (Box 1393, Folder 40)
- Class of 1882: Lester, Grace Darling 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 1)
- Class of 1882: Luck, Emma Josephine 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 2)
- Class of 1882: McClellan, Katherine Elizabeth (Box 1394, Folder 3)
- Class of 1882: McKee, Isabel Dinwiddie 1882, 1914 (Box 1394, Folder 4)
- Class of 1882: McKeown, Ella Maranda 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 5)
- Class of 1882: Merriam, Florence B. 1980 (Box 1394, Folder 6)
- Class of 1882: Milligan, Josephine Ewing 1882, 1922 (Box 1394, Folder 7)
- Class of 1882: Mix, Mary Jacob 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 8)
- Class of 1882: Palmer, Lucy White N.d. (Box 1394, Folder 9)
- Class of 1882: Palmes, Nannie Gertrude 1878-80, 1882, 1890 (Box 1394, Folder 10)
- Class of 1882: Peabody, Susan Perkins 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 11)
- Class of 1882: Pellett, Frances (Box 1394, Folder 12)
- Class of 1882: Peirce, Annie Calder 1876, 1878-79, 1906 (Box 1394, Folder 13)
- Class of 1882: Peloubet, Mary Alice 1882, 1902 (Box 1394, Folder 14)
- Class of 1882: Pettibone, Mary Cordelia 1880-82 (Box 1394, Folder 15)
- Class of 1882: Phillips, Nella Sumner 1879, 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 16)
- Class of 1882: Preston, Grace Alma (Box 1394, Folder 17)
- Class of 1882: Safford, Helen 1880, 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 18)
- Class of 1882: Smith, Clara Janet Augusta 1882, 1921 (Box 1394, Folder 19)
- Class of 1882: Smith, Theodate Louise (General) 1882, 1898, 1912, 1914 (Box 1394, Folder 20)
- Class of 1882: Smith, Theodate Louise (Writings) 1904, 1911-14 (Box 1394, Folder 21)
- Class of 1882: Snell, Harriet Margaret 1882, other n.d. (Box 1394, Folder 22)
- Class of 1882: Soule, Haidee Hobart 1882, 1889 (Box 1394, Folder 23)
- Class of 1882: Tenney, Mary Alice 1882, 1912, 1916, 1920-22, 1925, 1934 (Box 1394, Folder 24)
- Class of 1882: Tucker, Alice Elizabeth 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 25)
- Class of 1882: Vinton, Maria Mitchell 1882, 1899, 1912-14, 1916 (Box 1394, Folder 26)
- Class of 1882: Washburn, Clara Spencer 1882 (Box 1394, Folder 27)
- Class of 1882: Watson, Esther Josephine (Box 1394, Folder 28)
- Class of 1882: Wright, Elizabeth Boleyn 1882, 1894 (Box 1394, Folder 29)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Birth Record) 1859 (Box 1395, Folder 1)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Student Notes) N.d. (Box 1395, Folder 2)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Journal) 1876, 1879, 1880, 1882 (Box 1395, Folder 3)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Correspondence to Family: Jul, Sept, Jun, Oct) 1870-71, 1878 (Box 1395, Folder 4)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Correspondence to Family: Nov-Dec) 1878 (Box 1395, Folder 5)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Correspondence to Family: Jan-Feb) 1879 (Box 1395, Folder 6)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Correspondence to Family: Apr-Jun) 1879 (Box 1395, Folder 7)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Correspondence to Family: Jul-Dec) 1879 (Box 1395, Folder 8)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: Jan-Mar) 1880 (Box 1395, Folder 9)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: Apr-May) 1880 (Box 1395, Folder 10)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: Sept-Mar) 1880-1881 (Box 1395, Folder 11)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: Mar-Jun) 1881 (Box 1395, Folder 12)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: Sept-Dec) 1881 (Box 1395, Folder 13)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: Jan-Mar) 1882 (Box 1395, Folder 14)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: Apr-Jun) 1882-1883 (Box 1395, Folder 15)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family: May) 1886 (Box 1395, Folder 16)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick and Frona Marie (1883): (Correspondence to Family) N.d. (Box 1395, Folder 17)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Photographs) 1882, 1921, 1932 (Box 1395, Folder 18)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Adams, Mrs.) 1888 (Box 1395, Folder 19)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Allen, Annie) 1918, 1926-26, 1928, 1930-32, 1934-37) (Box 1395, Folder 20)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Brooks, Elizabeth) 1930 (Box 1395, Folder 21)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Brooks, Harriet) 1910 (Box 1395, Folder 22)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Brooks, Ina) 1907 (Box 1395, Folder 23)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Browne, Nina) 1917, 1920, 1922, 1934-37 (Box 1395, Folder 24)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Clark, Mrs. Levi) 1880-82 (Box 1395, Folder 25)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Foster, Mrs.) 1880 (Box 1395, Folder 26)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Gulliver, Mary) 1913, 1920-21 (Box 1395, Folder 27)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Kittredge, Frances) N.d. (Box 1395, Folder 28)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Knapp, Elizabeth P.) 1926, 1935 (Box 1395, Folder 29)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Lowry, Anna) 1920-21 (Box 1395, Folder 30)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Oughterson, Mrs. W.A.) 1920 (Box 1395, Folder 31)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Sedgwick, Mary) N.d. (Box 1395, Folder 32)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Sill, E.R.) 1881-82 (Box 1395, Folder 33)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Letters: Smith, Mrs.) 1917 (Box 1395, Folder 34)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Scrapbook) Late1870s-Mid 1880s (Box 1396)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Scrapbook) Late1870s-Mid 1880s (Box 1396)
- Class of 1882: Brooks, Esther Herrick (Scrapbook) Late1870s-Mid 1880s (Box 1396)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Correspondence: Jan-Jun, typed copies) 1880-1881 (Box 1397, Folder 1)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Correspondence: Sept-Dec, typed copies) 1881 (Box 1397, Folder 2)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Correspondence: Jan-Jun, typed copies) 1882 (Box 1397, Folder 3)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Correspondence: Jan-Jun, originals) 1880-1881 (Box 1397, Folder 4)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Correspondence: Sept-Dec, originals) 1881 (Box 1397, Folder 5)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Correspondence: Jan-Jun, originals) 1882 (Box 1397, Folder 6)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Correspondence) 1909-1949 (Box 1397, Folder 7)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor 1904 (Box 1397, Folder 8)
- Class of 1882: Larrison, Eleanor (Photographs) 1882 (Box 1397, Folder 9)
- Class of 1882: Pellett, Frances (Photographs) 1882 (Box 1398, Folder 1)
- Class of 1882: Pellett, Frances (Scrapbook) Early-Mid 1880s (Box 1398)